# **Antoine Soetewey**

antoinesoetewey.com

## Summary

I am a PhD candidate in statistics at UCLouvain in Belgium, within the Institute of Statistics, Biostatistics and Actuarial Sciences. My research interests focus on bio-statistical methods applied to cancer patients.

In parallel with my doctoral thesis, I am teaching assistant for several courses in statistics and probability at bachelor and master's level. I also provide trainings and consulting in data science, statistics and R programming for UCLouvain's technology platform for Statistical Methodology and Computing Service.

In my spare time, I write about statistics and code in R via my blog statsandr.com.

#### Education

2017 – Present	PhD in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium
	- Thesis: Life and health actuarial pricing: a biostatistics approach (supervisors: Prof.
	Catherine Legrand and Prof. Michel Denuit)

- All publications, posters and talks available at antoinesoetewey.com/research

## 2015 – 2016 **MSc in econometrics & operations research** – Maastricht University, Netherlands

- Thesis: *Combining professional and survey forecasts for macroeconomic data* (supervisor: Prof. Nalan Basturk)

#### 2013 – 2015 **MSc in economics** – KULeuven, Belgium

- Thesis: Negativity bias and framing effect in charity donations: a field experiment (supervisor: Prof. Jo Swinnen)
- Faculty exchange of one semester at University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, USA

#### 

## Experience

#### 2017 - Present **Teaching assistant in statistics** - UCLouvain, Belgium

- See all courses at antoinesoetewey.com/teaching

#### 2018 - Present Consultant and instructor in statistics, R programming and data science

- Statistical and data analysis consulting for researchers and students (see easystat.be) and for professionals and companies (see datanalyze.be)
- Instructor for UCLouvain's university certificates (SMCS): "Introduction to data analysis with R", "Junior data analyst" and "Practice of statistics with R"

## 2016 – 2017 **Data scientist** – Business & Decision, Belgium

- Involved in several projects focusing on data science and data visualization

## Technical skills & languages

### **Software**

- R (RStudio, R Markdown & Quarto, R Shiny), Jamovi, GitHub/GitLab,  $\LaTeX$
- Web development
- See examples of projects at antoinesoetewey.com/software

### Languages

- French (native), English (fluent), Dutch (basic)